Ah Caroline...come on in.Sit down. Thank.
卡洛琳，进来，请坐。谢谢。
So how's the dissertation planning going?
论文进行的怎么样了？
Well Dr Schulmann.I'm still having a lot of trouble deciding on a title.
舒尔曼博士，我在选择题目上还有许多困扰。
Well, that's perfectly normal at this stage.
在这个阶段很正常。
And this is what your tutorials will help you to do. Right.
这就是辅导课要帮你做的。是的。
What we'll do is jot down some points that might help you in your decision.
我们要做的是记下一些可能对你的选择有帮助的要点。
First of all, you have chosen your general topic area, haven't you?
首先，你已经选好了大概的题目范围了，是吗？
Yes, it's the fishing industry.
是的，是渔业。
Oh yes, that was one of the areas you mentioned.
是的，这是你提到过的一个领域。
Now, what aspects of the course are you good at?
课程的哪方面是你擅长的？
Well, I think I'm coping well with statistics, and I'm never bored by it. Good.Anything else?
我认为我擅长统计，我从不对此感到厌烦。很好，还有吗？
Well, I found computer modelling fascinating
我发现计算机建模很有意思，
I have no problem following what's being taught, whereas quite a few of my classmates find it difficult.
我完全能跟上老师讲的内容，而我的很多同学却认为它很难。
Well, that's very good. Do you think these might be areas you could bring into your dissertation?
很好。你觉得这些可以用到你的论文里吗？
Oh yes, if possible.It's just that I'm having difficulty thinking how I can do that.
是的，如果有可能的话。我只是在如何处理上有问题。
You see I feel I don't have sufficient background information.
我觉得我没有足够的背景知识。
I see.Well, do you take notes?
我明白了，你记笔记了吗？
I'm very weak at note-taking.
我不善于记笔记。
My teachers always used to say that.
我的老师总是这么说。
Well, I think you really need to work on these weaknesses before you go any further.
我认为你应该在进一步进行之前克服这些弱点
What do you suggest?
你的建议是什么？